CARLOS SAN MARTÍN TRUJILLO

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Phone: +56998304615 (CHILE)

<u>CV WEB</u>

<u>LINKEDIN PERFIL</u>

carlosanmartin@hotmail.com

More than 10 years of experience working as a Front End developer.

Oriented to precision, concern for aesthetics and with a proactive approach to operate both independently and in multidisciplinary team environments (Backend, Devops, UX etc.)

In my work career, I have been part of multiple projects in various companies in the field of E-commerce, Retail, Multinational Consulting Companies, Airlines, communications, design agencies, educational institutions, government institutions, among others.

I am passionate about web development and design, I enjoy working as a team to achieve quality results, I consider myself to have the ability to learn quickly and adapt to new environments, which has allowed me to successfully face technical challenges and deliver projects with great results.

Excellent interpersonal relationships, organization and management of agile methodologies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE



FEBRUARY 2018 - JUNE 2023

CENCOSUD S.A. FOR EASY.CL WEBSITE

FRONT END DEVELOPER LAYOUT - WEB / MOBILE / UI.

IBM WEBSPHERE COMMERCE

- Front end development cell member for maintenance and evolutionary developments for E-commerce IBM www.easy.cl
- Responsible for UI Development, layout and integration of easy.cl website re-design.
 Front team member to improve the website's user experience. Support and UI development for IBM ECommerce platform
- Responsible for Development, maintenance and evolutionary for React Headless
 project (Headless commerce is based on an architecture where front end and back end
 work independently. The system to send content consists of using APIS connected to
 elastic Search with data loaded from IBM commerce databases)

Tools used: React JS (class Components), javascript, API Rest, Jquery , AWS, CI/CD, Elastic Search, Kibana, App Search, Git, HTML5, CSS3, Agile methodologies, JIRA, Vs Code

VTEX COMMERCE

- Front end Cell Member for maintenance and evolutionary developments for Ecommerce VTEX www.easy.cl
- Responsible for UI Development, layout and integration of re- easy.cl website design.
 Maintenance and evolution for the VTEX ECommerce platform
- React Headless Checkout project development manager (Consumption of content via APIS connected to a BFF with data loaded from the Commerce VTEX databases)

Tools used: React JS (Function Components), Clean Arquitecture, javascript, API Rest, AWS, Git, CI/CD, HTML5, CSS3, Design System, Styled-components, Story Books, Atomic Desing, Metodologías ágiles, JIRA, Vs Code



JUNE 2013 - FEBRUARY 2018 (4 YEARS 9 MONTHS)

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

FRONTEND / LAYOUT - WEB / MOBILE / DESIGNER / UI.

• **CENCOSUD ACCOUNT - EASY.CL:** In charge of UI Development, layout and integration of easy.cl website re-design. Front team member to improve the website's user experience. Support and UI development for IBM ECommerce platform.

 LATAM AIRLINES ACCOUNT: In charge of UI Development for LAN account projects. Interface design, conceptualization, layout, graphic implementation, creation of CSS for PC and mobile versions, Crew Portal design and development, Creation of UI components for iPad mobile applications.

Tools used: HTML5, CSS3, Jquery, Jquerymobile, Bootstrap, Eclipse, Liferay

EL MERCURIO ACCOUNT: Online advertising El Mercurio S.A.: Development of interfaces, conceptualization, layout, graphic implementation, creation of CSS for PC and mobile versions, for online advertising project for Mercurio..
 Tools used:HTML5, CSS3, Jquery, Bootstrap, Visual Studio, Adobe Dreamweaver, Adobe Fireworks, Adobe photoshop.



JANUARY 2013 - MAY 2013 (5 MONTHS)

IPP, PROVIDENCE PROFESSIONAL INSTITUTE

MULTIMEDIA E-LEARNING DEVELOPER

- Multimedia development for career courses in blended mode.
- Courses developed in Flash CS6, HTML/CSS.
- Integration of courses in the EPIC platform

JANUARY 2008 - DECEMBER 2012 (5 YEARS)

OPENSOFT OPENSOFT S.A.

MULTIMEDIA DEVELOPER FRONT UI

- UI development for government entities and large companies in the national market such as: National Monuments, Terra, lansa, Ariztía, SAG, Finning, Ducasse, Monticcelo, Euroamerica, Aiep, Celfin, Santa Rita, Conchaytoro, Cristalchile, Enami, Loreal. (websites, intranets, workflows, custom systems among others.) All based on the company's own self-manageable platform.
- Management and adaptation of languages such as html, xml, css, jquery, actionscript, javascript, asp.

JANUARY 2003 - DECEMBER 2007 (5 YEARS)

IMAGEN @ GLOBAL*

IMAGEN GLOBAL S.A

LAYOUT DEVELOPER FRONT UI

- Creation of websites for mobile platforms. (iphone, android etc)
- Experience in development and production of communication and marketing strategies, comprehensive implementation of internet campaigns (development of websites, advertising banners, mailings, E - marketing), among others
- Management of graphic communication technologies and Front development (Photoshop, HTML, CSS, action script, javascript), software for audio and video editing. Projects focused on small and medium-sized businesses.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

UDEMY

Complete React Developer

2023

AWS

AWS Technical Essentials

2023

UDEMY

React Pro, React with TypeScript / Fernando Herrera

2022

UDEMY

React, from zero to expert by Fernando Herrera 2021

GLOBAL KNOWLEDGE

Programming Essentials for IBM WebSphere Commerce V7

2018

ACADEMIA MAC-PC

Javascript - jQuery - HTML Integration

2012 - 2013

DIGICAP

Responsive HTML5-CSS Web Design and Programming

2010 - 2011

INTERNATIONAL LANGUAGE SERVICE

Intermediate level English course

2002 - 2003

DUOC - UC

Professional Advertising with Graphic mention - Multimedia - Web

1995 - 2000